

CONTACT

01777608508



nazrulislamtusar@gmail.com



https://nitushar.pvaatoz.com/



Dill Mohammed Road, Dhaka Uddan,

Mohammedpur, Dhaka - 1207

SKILLS



I have experienced with developing website and web applications both Static and Dynamic. I am a full stack web developer with four year experience.

HTML	95%
CSS	85%
JavaScript	76%
JS Framework	60%



I can design and develop a database for a small and medium label company with SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle. Besides, I know PHP and its framework, also I know several framework of Javascript for backend work.

React.Js	75%
РНР	70%
PHP Framework	45%
MySQL	85%
Node.Js	65%
Laravel	35%

RESUME OF

Nazrul Islam Tushar

Web Developer and Software Engineer



CAREER SUMMARY-

I am a punctual, responsible and hard working person. I worked as a computer operator in my home city before. I worked as a web software developer online as a co- Freelancer.

I have worked developing my university course project. I made many kinds of web page templates on my own. I have good working experience in a coaching institute.

I have a research work in Artificial Intelligent, and I developed an automation system for vehicle monitoring management by advance learning.



WORK EXPERIENCE-

bdCalling IT Limited 2023 - 2024

I worked in **bdCalling IT Limited (Softvence)** as a Sales Executive for a year.

PVAIT

2021 - 2022

I worked with **PVAIT** as a backend developer and database designer for two years. I also work as a frontend developer for their website.

ITPVA

2020 - 2021

I worked for **ITPVA** as a full stack web developer. I developed their Complete website for their company for up to two years.

USASERVICE24

2019 - 2020

I worked for **USASERVICE24** as their full stack web developer. Besides, I designed and developed database for their system for two years.

I have research work in Artifitial Neural Network and Machine Learning field. And I have a publication on IEEE and Research Gate based on an automation system for vehicle monitoring management by advance learning.

My Conference paper titled:

"Vehicle Number Plate Detection System Using Image Processing Approach"

Paper Link: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10307006

DOI: 10.1109/ICCCNT56998.2023.10307006



I can design and develop a desktop application for an entire company including database with so many Programming languages and frameworks.

Python	95%
Python Library	70%
Data Science	55%
JAVA	80%
Dot Net/C#	57%
C	88%
C++	73%



I did so many research work for my academic work. I have experienced with Machine Learning Deep Learning and Data Science. I know several Advanced programming Languages and framework.

With I yellon	
Artificial Neural Network With Python	54%



I have also some experience with developing android application with java and flutter.

3370
45%



My Other's Qualifications bellow

Content Writing	93%
Logo Design, Banner Design, Card Design, ID Card Design	65%
MS EXCEL/Google Sheet	92%
MS Office/Google Doc	96%
Power Point	94%



EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Sciences (B.Sc) 2017 - 2022

I have completed my graduation in Computer Science and Engineering from Bangladesh University of Business and Technology (BUBT). Mirpur-2, Dhaka-1216 with CGPA: 2.89 out of 4.00

Higher School Certificate (H.S.C) 2015 - 2016

I have completed my Higher School Certificate from Boshurhat Government Mujib College, Companiganj, Noyakhali with GPA 2.19 out of 5.00

Secondary School Certificate (S.S.C) 2014 - 2016

I have completed my Secondary School Certificate from Kabirhat Model Junior High School, Kabirhat, Noyakhli with GPA 5.00 out of 5.00



PERSONAL INFORMATION -

Father name : Md. Mostofa Mother name : Halima Khatun Date if Birth : 20 january 1998

Religion : Islam Gender : Male Marital Status : Single : Bangladeshi Nationality

: Kabirhat, Noyakhali **Permanent Address**



Language Proficiency -

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Bangla	Best	Best	Best
English	Best	Best	Better
Hindi	None	None	Better



Other's Experience -

I have knowledge in problem solving. I have attended so many competitive programming event. And I have been solved up to 30 problem in deferent site's problem named CordeForces.com, .com, HeakerRank.com, HeakerEarth.com, uvaonlinejudge.com etc. I have a profile on stoptalk.com



My Hobbies -

Programming, Watching Movies, Web Series and Travelling.

I undersigned, declaring that the information provided in this Curriculum Vitae is true. I always ready to submit the necessary evidence/papers as required. I am very much interested and I truly need this job, I am well skilled and a few experienced. So I believe I can do my job perfectly with my hard work, patients and what I know.

For more about me, visit my personal website: (link bellow)

https://nitushar.pvaatoz.com/